<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interview-prep on Nick Palenchar 👨‍💻</title>
    <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/tags/interview-prep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interview-prep on Nick Palenchar 👨‍💻</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:40:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nickpalenchar.com/tags/interview-prep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yes, GitHub Really Does Help Your Resume.</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:40:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/github/</guid>
      <description>When my employer is hiring, I&amp;rsquo;m the first to want to refer a good person. I&amp;rsquo;ll reach out to my network of bootcamp grads, asking for resumes, hoping I can get them a job at a great company.
I end up throwing out 99% of them every time.
The reason is always the same: their GitHub has half a year or much more of total radio silence.
If there&amp;rsquo;s one piece of advice I could shout from the rooftops, especially to new devs, is that an active GitHub is probably your best competitive advantage to getting an interview or referral cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interviewer once asked me how I would build a url-shortener app. After discussion, I decided to actually do it. Here&#39;s what I designed (and how you can contribute to the Open Source project)</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 10:22:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>About a year back I had an on-site interview at a very large finance company. I spent the day meeting engineers from every department, and was asked to whiteboard solutions to many problems. Some were very mathmatical algorithms, others were architectures for things like microservices and AWS. Among the questions, my favorite was making a URL shortener, similar to bit.ly.
THE CHALLENGE Design a URL shortener app. It should have a dashboard for users that can submit a link to be shortened.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
