<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Palenchar 👨‍💻</title>
    <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nick Palenchar 👨‍💻</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:40:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nickpalenchar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yes, GitHub Really Does Help Your Resume.</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:40:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/github/</guid>
      <description>When my employer is hiring, I&amp;rsquo;m the first to want to refer a good person. I&amp;rsquo;ll reach out to my network of bootcamp grads, asking for resumes, hoping I can get them a job at a great company.
I end up throwing out 99% of them every time.
The reason is always the same: their GitHub has half a year or much more of total radio silence.
If there&amp;rsquo;s one piece of advice I could shout from the rooftops, especially to new devs, is that an active GitHub is probably your best competitive advantage to getting an interview or referral cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Worst Blogging Advice I Ever Received</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/worst-blogging-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 13:17:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/worst-blogging-advice/</guid>
      <description>No annoying intro here. This is it:
&amp;ldquo;When starting a blog, be sure to update it regularly&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve actually heard or read this general &amp;ldquo;nugget&amp;rdquo; many times. It is as ubiquitous as it is terrible. One reason is that it&amp;rsquo;s only applicable to one type of blog. The kind that is monetized, relying on a large group of subscribers, with aspirations of generating a livable wage for the author. Obviously, there are many types of blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Changing Git Commands You Probably Aren&#39;t Using.</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 10:28:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/git/</guid>
      <description>Every developer uses some kind of version-control system (sometimes called VCS). It a fail-safe to losing work, allowing you to jump back in time and reference files as they once were. Because branching is supported, so much more than linearly stepping back in time is possible. VCS is the backbone for agile collaboration, allowing each developer to have their own copy of some codebase, where they can work at their own pace and merge changes back into a master copy when ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consider Less Anonymous Functions</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/anonymous-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 10:26:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/anonymous-functions/</guid>
      <description>This post is about coding style. What is coding style? It&amp;rsquo;s a conscious choice in the way the author writes code where such writing is justified by what the author is trying to express. It is not a &amp;ldquo;best practice&amp;rdquo;, nor is it appropriate in all situations. But it&amp;rsquo;s great for reflection. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about anonymous functions (specifically in JavaScript), and what happens when I use them less often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interviewer once asked me how I would build a url-shortener app. After discussion, I decided to actually do it. Here&#39;s what I designed (and how you can contribute to the Open Source project)</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 10:22:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>About a year back I had an on-site interview at a very large finance company. I spent the day meeting engineers from every department, and was asked to whiteboard solutions to many problems. Some were very mathmatical algorithms, others were architectures for things like microservices and AWS. Among the questions, my favorite was making a URL shortener, similar to bit.ly.
THE CHALLENGE Design a URL shortener app. It should have a dashboard for users that can submit a link to be shortened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 Habits of Highly Effective Node Clis</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/node-clis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 10:17:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/node-clis/</guid>
      <description>title:The 7 Habits of Highly Node CLIs (And how to make your own!) tags:coding,node,javascript date:02/28/2018
I love building CLI&amp;rsquo;s, and I recommend everyone learning to code build one (or more!). It will teach you a lot about how computers work at a slightly more in-depth level than web browser JavaScript. There one of my favorite types of projects, often done at work. However, I recently finished building the open source CLI, giftwrap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proactive Approach to Impostor Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 10:01:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>We all know about Imposter Syndrome yet the epidemic seems to be growing, especially when breaking into a new career (like those learning to code). No doubt I&amp;rsquo;ve felt it in tech and elsewhere in life, as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you have. While there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of articles and videos on how to fight the self-doubt that comes along with Imposter Syndrome, I&amp;rsquo;d like to offer an alternative approach:
Use it.
You can try to fight Impostor Syndrome or change your mindset, and doing so has worked for some people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Maybe Learn to Code</title>
      <link>https://nickpalenchar.com/please-maybe-learn-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 10:33:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickpalenchar.com/please-maybe-learn-to-code/</guid>
      <description>Please don’t learn to code. Please do learn to code. This past week, a blogospheric angel and devil has emerged on both sides of my shoulders after the latest and greatest installment of opinions manifested on the internet.
I read the Tech Crunch article. I read the FreeCodeCamp article. For good measure, I also read the Coding Horror article mentioned by the FreeCodeCamp article. My reaction? They all have valid points and are all worth reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
